Robert Hare Papers 1764-1859 Mss.B.H22
American Philosophical Society
- Series II. Robert Hare Scrolls
  - For the New York Herald, concerning Hare's paper read before the Academie des Sciences, Paris, on tornadoes, Robert Hare (Box 8)
  - For the New York Herald. On the great political fissure - by an anti-Jeffersonian, Robert Hare (Box 8)
  - For the United States Gazette on "Impolicy of Protective Duties", Robert Hare (Box 8)
  - The government of the U.S. a demagoguery, Robert Hare (Box 8)
  - Gas ram: for raising water or propelling vessels, Robert Hare (Box 8)
  - Hail Celestial Liberty poem, Robert Hare (Box 8)
  - Hydrostatic pressure used for public water supply, Robert Hare (Box 8)
  - Hymn, to the tune of "When clouds and storms obscure the Skies", Robert Hare (Box 8)
  - Importance of facilitating the hydrogenation or carbonization of nitrogen, Robert Hare (Box 8)
  - Lecture: Introductory to a course on chemistry in the University of Pennsylvania, Robert Hare (Box 8)
  - Lecture on chemistry, Robert Hare (Box 8)
  - Letter to Alexander Dallas Bache on weights and measures, Robert Hare (Box 9)
  - Letter to Langdon Cheves, Robert Hare (Box 9)
  - Letter to Langdon Cheves on Jefferson, Robert Hare (Box 9)
  - Letter to William Read (?) on theory of storms, Robert Hare (Box 9)
  - Letter to the editors of the Franklin Journal, Robert Hare (Box 9)
  - Letter to the "Editors" of the Intelligencer, Robert Hare (Box 9)
  - Letter to Messrs Gales and Seaton on the report of Mr. Hunter as chairman of the finance committee of the U.S. Senate, Robert Hare (Box 9)
  - Letter to Joseph Henry concerning chemical apparatus, Robert Hare (Box 9)
  - Letter to Joseph Henry in re the gift of his apparatus to the Smithsonian Institution, Robert Hare (Box 9)
  - Letter to Freeman Hunt, Robert Hare (Box 9)
  - Letter to the National Intelligencer, Robert Hare (Box 9)
  - Letter to Charles Partridge on spiritualism and the Bible, 1857 Feb. 6; Robert Hare (Box 9)
  - Letter to Messrs Partridge and Brittan, Robert Hare (Box 9)
  - Letter to the Regents of the Smithsonian Institution, Robert Hare (Box 9)
  - Letter to William Reid on theory of storms, Robert Hare (Box 9)
  - Letter to Dr. Rogers on breaking ice on the Delaware, Robert Hare (Box 9)
  - Letter to Benjamin Silliman, Robert Hare (Box 9)
  - Letter to ----, December 8, 1856; Robert Hare (Box 9)
  - List of apparatus, Robert Hare (Box 9)
  - List of chemicals, Robert Hare (Box 9)
  - The Medical Faculty to the Board of Trustees of the University of Pennsylvania, Robert Hare (Box 9)
  - Objections a la nomenclature du Celebre Berzelius, Robert Hare (Box 9)
  - Objections to the idea that there has been change in atomic elements, Robert Hare (Box 9)
  - Observations sur l'ether sulphate, Robert Hare (Box 9)
  - Ocular evidence of the absurdity of the view that storms are travelling whirlwinds, Robert Hare (Box 9)
  - Of mind as existing independently, and as distinguished from matter, Robert Hare (Box 9)
  - Of mundane, ethereal and ponderable matter, in their chemical relations, Robert Hare (Box 9)
  - Of the gales experienced in the Atlantic states of the U.S., Robert Hare (Box 9)
  - On a tornado, Robert Hare (Box 9)
  - On agriculture, Robert Hare (Box 9)
    Originally as a scroll; flattened, Oct. 1974. Filed with Series I: Correspondence.
  - On an article in the Ledger suggesting that alcohol is the basis of food for animals, Robert Hare (Box 9)
  - On blasting rocks under water, Robert Hare (Box 9)
  - On capital punishment, Robert Hare (Box 9)
  - On chemistry, Robert Hare (Box 9)
  - On chemistry in China, Robert Hare (Box 9)
  - On currency and the need for specie, Robert Hare (Box 9)
  - On cycloidal storms, Robert Hare (Box 9)
  - On democratic government in the U.S., Robert Hare (Box 10)
  - On democracy, Robert Hare (Box 10)
  - On democracy in government, Robert Hare (Box 10)
  - On demagogueocracy and the misreprensentation of the part taken by the Federalists and Jeffersonians respecting slavery, Robert Hare (Box 10)
  - On electromagnetism, Robert Hare (Box 10)
  - On electro-polarity as the cause of electrical phenomena, Robert Hare (Box 10)
  - On Emerson, Robert Hare (Box 10)
  - On Faraday's idea of the nature of matter, Robert Hare (Box 10)
  - On French despotism, Robert Hare (Box 10)
  - On good breeding, Robert Hare (Box 10)
  - On inventions, Robert Hare (Box 10)
  - On Mr. John Wises observations and inferences respecting the phenomena of a thunderstorm to which he was exposed during an aerostatic voyage, 3 June 1852; Robert Hare (Box 10)
  - On liberty of the press in the U.S., Robert Hare (Box 10)
  - On life after death religion, Robert Hare (Box 10)
  - On local politics, Robert Hare (Box 10)
  - On making weights for a system of weights and measures, Robert Hare (Box 10)
  - On poverty, Robert Hare (Box 10)
  - On religion, Robert Hare (Box 10)
  - On slavery, Robert Hare (Box 10)
  - On slavery in the United States, Robert Hare (Box 10)
  - On soap, Robert Hare (Box 10)
  - On spiritualism, Robert Hare (Box 10)
  - On storms, Robert Hare (Box 10)
  - On Sumner and slavery, Robert Hare (Box 10)
  - On the absurdity of supposing hydrogen by its explosiveness to cause the bursting of steam engine boilers, Robert Hare
  - On the advantages of living under a democratic republican government, Robert Hare (Box 11)
  - On the claims of Texas, Robert Hare (Box 11)
  - On the democratic system in the United States, Robert Hare (Box 11)
  - On the Democratic Whig Party and the Federlists Black Cockade, Robert Hare (Box 11)
  - On the election of Thomas Jefferson as president of the American Philosophical Society, undated
  - On the European chemists, Robert Hare (Box 11)
  - On the Great Political Fissure, Robert Hare (Box 11)
  - On the Great Political Fissure, by an anti-Jeffersonian, Robert Hare (Box 11)
  - On the motion of planets, Robert Hare (Box 11)
  - On the necessity of special laws as well as general laws to the origination and endurance of the Creation, Robert Hare (Box 11)
  - On the patronage given chemistry by governments, Robert Hare (Box 11)
  - On the prevention of putrefaction, Robert Hare (Box 11)
  - On the registry of the African race, Robert Hare (Box 11)
  - Registry of the African race as a substitute for the plan of preventing the settlement of negroes or mulattoes in the State of Pennsylvania, Robert Hare (Box 11)
  - On the success of a republican form of government, Robert Hare (Box 11)
  - On the selfishness of mankind, whether rich or poor, Robert Hare (Box 11)
  - On the speculation of Farady on the nature of matter, Robert Hare (Box 11)
  - On the success of the U.S. government, Robert Hare (Box 11)
  - On the suppositious travelling whirlwinds called cyclones, Robert Hare (Box 11)
  - On the theory of storms, Robert Hare (Box 11)
  - On tornadoes, Robert Hare (Box 11)
  - The origin of the passion of love like parental affection dependent on an idea, Robert Hare (Box 12)
  - Poem, using chemical terms, Robert Hare (Box 12)
  - Processes devised for the prevention of putrefaction, Robert Hare (Box 12)
  - Project for preventing carcasses and other perishable matter from becoming a nuisance and for the conversion of them into a guano, Robert Hare (Box 12)
  - Reasons for refusing to become vice-president for the City-County Consolidation Committee, Robert Hare (Box 12)
  - Refutation des arguments avancees en faveur de l'existences, dans les sals amphides..., Robert Hare (Box 12)
  - Reply to his "Spiritualism Scientifically Demonstrated" answered, Robert Hare (Box 12)
  - Researches on the article on chemistry from the Scientific American, Robert Hare (Box 12)
  - Rough draft of article on War of 1812, Robert Hare (Box 12)
  - Self regulating reservoirs for chlorine, Robert Hare (Box 12)
  - The selfishness of mankind, whether rich or poor; Is the great foe of true democracy, Robert Hare (Box 12)
  - Some advantages in having a currency which cannot be expected to pay foreign debts, Robert Hare (Box 12)
  - Some ideas suggested by the preamble to the resolutions of the Alabama Legislature, in favour of the annexation of Texas, submitted to Congress in 1838, Robert Hare (Box 12)
  - Storms strictures on Pettier's inferences, Robert Hare (Box 12)
  - Strictures on an article on the riots in the suburbs of Philadelphia, Robert Hare (Box 12)
  - Suggestions supplementary to a communication made to the American Association for the Advancement of Science respecting Espy's report on storms, Robert Hare (Box 12)
  - Supplementary communication on the causes of tornadoes, made to the American Association for the Advancement of Science, Robert Hare (Box 12)
  - The surmise that tornadoes may be due to the same agency as eddy whirlwinds proved to be erroneous, Robert Hare (Box 12)
  - Synopsis of my labors, Robert Hare (Box 12)
  - Synopsis on the suppositious travelling whirlwinds called cyclones, Robert Hare (Box 12)
  - Thoughts on the creation of a national bank, Robert Hare (Box 12)
  - To Messrs Gale and Seaton on liberty in the United States, Robert Hare (Box 12)
  - To the Commissioner of Patents, on concentrated manure, 1848 Nov.
    Originally as scroll; laminated 1963. Filed with Series I: Correspondence.
  - To the Editor of the National Gazette, in re the banking system of United States, Robert Hare (Box 12)
  - To the Editor of the Philadelphia Gazette, on the American Cockade, wherein Samuel Breck is refuted. Also, an address from the young men of Philadelphia to President John Adams, etc., Robert Hare (Box 12)
  - To the Editors of the Franklin Journal, concerning the specific heats of elastic fluids by Regnaud, Robert Hare (Box 12)
  - To the Editors of the North American: On the means of arresting extensive conflagrations, Robert Hare (Box 12)
  - To the Inquirer on currency, Robert Hare (Box 12)
  - To the National Intelligencer on the exclusion from the royal levee, Robert Hare (Box 12)
  - To the North American: a peace offering to the south by one who is opposed to all unconstitutional opposition to slave holding, Robert Hare (Box 12)
  - To the North American. Refuting charges against "our excellent president", Robert Hare (Box 12)
  - To the Pennsylvania Inquirer, on cycloidal curvature, Robert Hare (Box 12)
  - To the President of the Agricultural Society of the United States, Robert Hare (Box 12)
  - To the Senate and House of Representatives of the U.S. in re: studies of the causes of storms, Robert Hare (Box 12)
  - Translation of the refutation of the salt radical theory, Robert Hare (Box 12)
  - Upon the influence of icebergs upon the climate of the United States, Robert Hare (Box 12)
  - Views respecting slavery and peonage, sanctioned by the spirits of Washington,Franklin, Calhoun, and those of many distinguished anti-slavery philanthropists, Robert Hare (Box 12)
  - Verses, Robert Hare (Box 12)
  - Verses on various subjects, Robert Hare (Box 12)
  - Robert Hare for the American Journal of Science. Concerning an idea by Faraday (Box 12)
  - Thomas D. Rotch to Robert Hare (Box 12)
  - Duncan McKean to Robert Hare, 1856 November 11 (Box 12)
    Originally as a scroll; flattened, August 1974. Filed with Series I: Correspondence.
    On spiritualism and religion.
  - Benjamin Silliman to Robert Hare, 1857 May (Box 12)
    On Spiritualism and Christianity.
  - R. P. Stevens to Robert Hare concerning tornadoes and water-spouts (Box 12)